Guide to the Stereograph File [1855-1964] (Bulk 1860-1900) PR 65
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
Stereograph File
[1855-1964]
PR 65
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
82.0 Linear feet (17,301 items)
The Stereograph File consists of materials published in the stereographic form, which when seen through a viewer gives the impression of being a three dimensional representation. The bulk of the collection consists of paper stereographs (which range in size from 3 1/8 x 6 3/4 inches to 4 x 7 inches) published between 1860-1900, including albumen and silver gelatin prints. There are also early glass stereographs, tissue stereographs, tintypes, and photomechanically produced views. The views were acquired from a variety of sources over the last 130 years and represent of the work of a large variety of photographers and publishers. Most of the collection depicts identifiable geographic locations or subject matter. There are a numer of Civil War stereographs; these have been digitized and and are available online via New York Heritage. There are also views that were staged in a dramatic fashion to tell or story or convey emotional content.
Provenance
The majority of the Stereograph File is from the collection of George T. Bagoe, and was donated by Mrs. Elihu Spicer in 1960-1961. Another series was taken by Alfred C. Loonam in the 1950s and 1960s, and donated by his wife. Others were purchased, or transferred from other institutions. There are over 300 accession dates and numerous sources recorded in the database.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers, by appointment only.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to 30 photocopies per day per person. Suitability of the original for photocopying is at the discretion of the staff. Neither blueprints nor tracings can be copied under any circumstances. Duplication of large-format items will be done by the house photographer. See Print Room guidelines for details.
Historical Note
Over 800 photographers and publishers created the work represented in the Stereograph File. Major publishers including E & H.T. Anthony, Keystone, Underwood & Underwood and Kilburn Brothers make up much of the collection. Views by well-known western photographers Carleton Watkins, William Henry Jackson, J.J. Reilly and C.R. Savage are included, along with photographers who worked in eastern locales such as John P. Soule, D. Barnum, the Bierstadt Brothers, and George Barker. Many of the photographers worked in established tourist areas, such as Niagara Falls however, dozens of photographers working in their local areas are also included in the file. Portraitists who worked in stereo include Mathew Brady, Pach Brothers, Napoleon Sarony and J. Gurney & Son. Some of the photographers were amateurs, such as F. F. Thompson, who photographed Central Park in the 1860s and was one of the founders of the Amateur Photographic Exchange Club. Another significant amateur was Alfred T. Loonam, whose stereographs of New York in the 1950s and 1960s capture modern skyscrapers, expressways under construction, and the emerging television industry.
Scope and Content Note
Views in the Stereograph File depict a wide range of subject matter. Most of the items show known locations, and over one third of the collection depicts New York state. 4,000 of these items depict New York City. Other well-represented geographic locations include California, with 739 items, Massachusetts with 598, Pennsylvania with 798, New Hampshire with 475, Washington, D.C. with 320, New Jersey with 226 and Connecticut with 210. Subject areas with substantial holdings include the Civil War, Indians of North America, and the expeditions in the west led by Fisk, Hayden, Powell and Wheeler. The Civil War stereographs have been digitized and and are available online via New York Heritage.There are also a substantial number of portraits, primarily those of celebrities.
Items in the series that are arranged geographically depict homes, churches and other institutions and organizations, public buildings, offices, schools, restaurants, farms, businesses and industries, and include some interior views. Industries that are well represented include mining, logging, shipping, and the early petroleum industry in Pennsylvania. Because of a personal interest on the part of George T. Bagoe, who collected many of the stereographs in the file, the files contain many views of photographers or their studios or equipment. Sometimes the views depict historically significant sites, such as the Old North Church in Boston, and the armory where John Brown was captured in Harper's Ferry.
Many types of transportation are depicted. Railroads, particularly the Central and Union Pacific, and the Pennsylvania Railroads are well represented. There are images of the Erie and Delaware and Hudson canals, as well as ocean and river shipping. Stagecoaches, carriages, carts and wagons, omnibuses and street-railroads are seen in street views and in the country. Elevated railroads and the subway in New York City are documented, and even modern expressways were photographed in stereo and included in the file.
Community activities such as parades, anniversaries of historic events and holidays such as the Fourth of July are documented, as well as the sports of rowing, croquet, archery, horseback riding and hunting. Other activities for enlightenment and amusement photographed include camp meetings and chatauquas, reading, band concerts, circuses, merry-go-rounds, and picnicking.
Tourist attractions are also well represented, including Niagara Falls, the Grand Canyon and mountains in New Hampshire and Colorado, and hot and mineral springs. Also present are souvenirs of the Centennial Exposition of 1876, and the World's Columbian Exposition, as well as exhibitions in the Crystal Palace in London and various expositions in Paris.
Photographers and publishers also took advantage of spectacular events to produce and market stereographs, including, balloon ascensions, Blondin crossing Niagara Falls on tightrope, the Chicago and Boston fires, the San Francisco earthquake, train wrecks, dam failures, tornado damage and other disasters. Scientific discoveries and technological advances were a focus of public interest in the nineteenth century and are also represented in the stereographs. Feats of engineering such as canals, railroads, aqueducts and bridges are well represented. In addition there are views showing a fascination for scientific advances and discoveries, such as images of the fraudulent Cardiff Giant, and views of the full moon.
There are many kinds of people depicted in the file. The official visits of the Japanese embassy, the Prince of Wales and the Grand Duke of Russia in the 1860s are all documented. Other foreign-born individuals are identified, including Chinese laborers in Massachusetts and California, and Irish-, German-, and Scandinavian Americans. African Americans are depicted in many locales, as are Native Americans. A fascination with people with different life-styles is evident in the images of the Shakers, the Oneida Community and the Mormons. The collection database provides indexing for various classes of people, such as women, and children.
War has offered perennial subject matter for stereographers. Some of the earliest views in the collection show Crimean War sites. Besides the heavily documented United States Civil War, other military actions that were recorded include the Modoc Indian War, the Spanish American War, South African War (Boer War), the Russo-Japanese War, and World War I. Usually the scenes do not show battle action, but are important for the images of soldiers, battlefields, armaments and important persons related to the war.
Arrangement
Within each series the stereographs are arranged by photographer's or publisher's name. If the photographer or publisher had assigned numbers to the views, the views will be further delineated by those numbers.
The collection is arranged into 905 series. The bulk of the series cover various geographical locations. Wherever possible items are arranged in the smallest geographic unit possible, usually a town. Large cities may be covered by many series and the views divided up by location within the city, or by subject. If there are only one or two items for a particular geographic unit, they may be combined with other items and described under the name of the next larger geographic unit, such as the state. In general, the file goes from the general to the specific, series covering entire states followed by more specific locations within the state.
Other stereographs in the collection are arranged into subject series. Many of the items arranged by subject are of unknown location. Other subjects have known locations, but depict substantial and important subjects, such as the Civil War or the Spanish American War. Some of the items form published series, such as the Powell and Wheeler expeditions in the American West. It may be necessary to search the geographic series for subjects that are also represented in the subject series. For instance, there is a subject series titled Indians of North America, and there are views with this subject matter dispersed throughout the geographic files.
Finally, there are views that were staged to tell a story or to depict a scene from literature, which are filed under the general heading Comic and Sentimental. These are divided up by published series, or general topic.
Related Material at The New-York Historical Society
The Transparency file includes stereoscopic views, including glass and film views. There are some stereoscopic lantern slides, as well as a large number of Stereo Realist format slides. The Cased Photograph File includes stereographic daguerreotypes.
Barker, George, 1844-1894, photographer; Bierstadt Brothers, photographers; Brady, Mathew B., 1823 (ca.)-1896, photographer; Centennial Exhibition (1876: Philadelphia, Pa.); E. & H.T. Anthony (Firm), publishers; Geological Survey of the Territories (U.S.); J. Gurney & Son, photographers; Jackson, William Henry, 1843-1942, photographer; Keystone View Company, publisher; Kilburn Brothers, publisher; Loonam, Alfred T., photographer; Pach Brothers, photographers; Sarony, Napoleon, 1812-1863, photographer; Soule, John P., photographer; Thompson, F.F., photographer; Underwood & Underwood, publisher; Watkins, Carleton E., 1829-1916, photographer; World's Columbian Exposition (1893: Chicago, Ill.); Afro-Americans; Albumen prints; Associations, institutions, etc.--United States; California; Camp meetings--United States; Canals--United States; Chinese Americans; Colorado River (Colo.-Mex.)--Discovery and exploration; Crimean War, 1853-1856; Diplomats-- Japan; Disasters--United States; Exhibitions; Gelatin silver prints; Great Fire, Chicago, Ill., 1871; Historic sites--United States; Indians of North America; Interiors; Mines and mineral resources--United States; Modoc Indians--Wars, 1873; New York (State); Niagara Falls (N.Y. and Ont.); Parades; Parks; Pennsylvania; Petroleum industry and trade--United States; Photographers; Photographic prints; Photomechanical prints; Portraits; Public buildings; Railroads--United States; Schools--United States; Shakers; Shipping; Souvenirs; Spanish-American War, 1898; Stereographs; Tourism--United States; United States--Discovery and exploration; United States--History-- Civil War, 1861-1865; World War, 1914-1918
  - Alabama, 1900 (Box 1)
  - Alaska, 1866 - [1910] (Box 1)
  - Alaska--Gold rush, 1898 - 1902 (Box 1)
  - Alaska--Gold rush--Chilkoot Pass, 1898 (Box 1)
  - Arizona, [1870 - 1879] (Box 1)
  - Arizona--Grand Canyon, 1903 - 1909 (Box 1)
  - Arizona--Indians of North America, [187-] - 1903 (Box 1)
  - Arkansas, [1870 - 1879] (Box 1)
  - California, 1865 - 1900 (Box 2)
  - California--Big Trees, [187-] - 1901 (Box 2)
  - California--Central Pacific RR & Sierras, 1866 - [188-] (Box 2)
  - California--Geysers, [187-] - [188-] (Box 2)
  - California--Gold mining, 1866 - [1880] (Box 3)
  - California--Los Angeles, [187-] - [1905] (Box 3)
  - California--Modoc War, 1873 (Box 3)
  - California--Sacramento, [1860] - [1880] (Box 3)
  - California--San Francisco, [187-] - [188-] (Box 3)
  - California--San Francisco, [1860] - 1904 (Box 4)
  - California--San Francisco--by Watkins, 1862 - [188-] (Box 4)
  - California--San Francisco--Fire, 1906 (Box 4)
  - California--Santa Barbara, [187-] - 1902 (Box 4)
  - California--Stockton, 1865 - [1885] (Box 4)
  - California--Yosemite, [1865] - 1906 (Box 5)
  - Colorado, [1867-] - [19--] (Box 5)
  - Colorado--Mountain and RR views, 1866 - 1898 (Box 6)
  - Colorado--Black Hawk, 1867 - [188-] (Box 6)
  - Colorado--Central City, 1867 - [188-] (Box 6)
  - Colorado--Clear Creek Canyon, 1867 - [188-] (Box 6)
  - Colorado--Colorado Springs & Pikes Peak, 1871 - 1894 (Box 6)
  - Colorado--Denver, 1867 - 1883 (Box 6)
  - Colorado--Fort Lyon, [1870] - [1879] (Box 6)
  - Colorado--Garden of the Gods, 1866 - 1906 (Box 6)
  - Colorado--Georgetown, 1867 - 1904 (Box 6)
  - Colorado--Leadville, [186-] - [188-] (Box 6)
  - Colorado--Manitou, 1870 - [188-] (Box 6)
  - Colorado--Platte Canyon, 1870 - [188-] (Box 6)
  - Colorado--Royal Gorge, 1870 - [188-] (Box 7)
  - Colorado--Ute Pass and Williams Canyon, 1870 - [188-] (Box 7)
  - Connecticut, [186-] - [188-] (Box 7)
  - Connecticut--Bristol, [1880] - [1889] (Box 7)
  - Connecticut--Hartford, 1865 - 1890 (Box 7)
  - Connecticut--Meriden, [186-] - 1881 (Box 7)
  - Connecticut--Middletown, [187-] - [189-] (Box 7)
  - Connecticut--New Britain, [187-] - [188-] (Box 7)
  - Connecticut--New Haven, 1865 - [188-] (Box 7)
  - Connecticut--New London, 1865 - [188-] (Box 7)
  - Connecticut--Norwalk, [186-] - 1880 (Box 7)
  - Connecticut--Norwich, 1865 - 1880 (Box 7)
  - Connecticut--Tariffville Bridge train wreck, 1878 (Box 8)
  - Connecticut--Wallingford tornado, 1878 (Box 8)
  - Connecticut--Waterbury, [187-] - [188-] (Box 8)
  - Delaware, [186-] - [187-] (Box 8)
  - District of Columbia, 1866 - [188-] (Box 8)
  - District of Columbia--Panoramas, 1865 - 1903 (Box 8)
  - District of Columbia--Agriculture, Botanic Gardens, 1868 - [189-] (Box 8)
  - District of Columbia--Capitol, 1866 - 1906 (Box 8)
  - District of Columbia--Capitol--Senate and House, 1863 - [189-] (Box 8)
  - District of Columbia--Corcoran Gallery of Art, [186-] - [188-] (Box 8)
  - District of Columbia--Events, 1865 - 1910 (Box 8)
  - District of Columbia--Georgetown, 1866 - [188-] (Box 8)
  - District of Columbia--Library of Congress, 1866 - 1902 (Box 8)
  - District of Columbia--Navy yard, [187-] - [188-] (Box 8)
  - District of Columbia--Patent Office, 1866 - 1891 (Box 9)
  - District of Columbia--Pennsylvania Avenue, 1865 - 1903 (Box 9)
  - District of Columbia--Post Office, 1866 - [188-] (Box 9)
  - District of Columbia--Smithsonian Institution, [1866] -1890 (Box 9)
  - District of Columbia--State, Navy and War Departments, 1866 - 1891 (Box 9)
  - District of Columbia--Statuary, 1858 - 1890 (Box 9)
  - District of Columbia--Treasury, [186-] - [188-] (Box 9)
  - District of Columbia--Washington Monument, [186-] - 1902 (Box 9)
  - District of Columbia--White House, 1866 - 1902 (Box 9)
  - District of Columbia--White House--Interior, [186-] - 1908 (Box 9)
  - Florida, [187-] - 1904 (Box 10)
  - Florida--Fernandina, 1865 - 1880 (Box 10)
  - Florida--Indian River, [1880] - [1889] (Box 10)
  - Florida--Jacksonville, [187-] - [188-] (Box 10)
  - Florida--Mandarin--Stowe residence, 1880 (Box 10)
  - Florida--Oklawaha River, [187-] - 1892 (Box 10)
  - Florida--Saint Augustine, 1865 - 1905 (Box 10)
  - Florida--St. Johns River, 1866 - 1890 (Box 10)
  - Georgia, [186-] - [188-] (Box 10)
  - Georgia--Atlanta, 1864 - 1895 (Box 10)
  - Georgia--Bonaventure, [1870] - [1879] (Box 10)
  - Georgia--Savannah, [186-] - [188-] (Box 11)
  - Hawaii, [190-] - [191-] (Box 11)
  - Idaho, 1872 - [188-] (Box 11)
  - Illinois, 1865 - 1908 (Box 11)
  - Illinois--Chicago, [186-] - 1908 (Box 11)
  - Illinois--Chicago--Fire, 1871 (Box 11)
  - Illinois--Chicago--Fire, 1871 (Box 12)
  - Illinois--Chicago--World's Columbian Exposition, 1893 (Box 12)
  - Indiana, [187-] - [189-] (Box 12)
  - Iowa, 1868 - [188-] (Box 12)
  - Iowa--Muscatine, [1870] - [1879] (Box 12)
  - Kansas, [187-] - 1907 (Box 12)
  - Kansas--Leavenworth, [1870] - [1879] (Box 13)
  - Kansas; Missouri--Union Pacific Railroad--by Gardner, 1867 - 1868 (Box 13)
  - Kentucky, [187-] - 1909 (Box 13)
  - Kentucky--Mammoth Caves--Proctor & O'Shaughnessey, 1866 (Box 13)
  - Louisiana, 1871 (Box 13)
  - Louisiana--New Orleans, 1860 - 1902 (Box 13)
  - Maine, [187-] - [188-] (Box 13)
  - Maine--Bar Harbor/Mt. Desert, 1867 - [187-] (Box 13)
  - Maine--Camden, 1865 - 1885 (Box 13)
  - Maine--Eads Falls, Naples, 1900 (Box 13)
  - Maine--Hunting, [1870] (Box 13)
  - Maine--Kennebago Lake, [1880] - [1889] (Box 13)
  - Maine--Old Orchard Beach, [187-] - [188-] (Box 13)
  - Maine--Portland, [186-] - 1881 (Box 13)
  - Maryland, [1870] - [1879] (Box 13)
  - Maryland--Annapolis, 1870 (Box 13)
  - Maryland--Baltimore, [186-] - [188-] (Box 14)
  - Massachusetts, 1862 - 1900 (Box 14)
  - Massachusetts--Beverly, [1870] - [1879] (Box 14)
  - Massachusetts--Boston--General, street, harbor views, 1859 - 1910 (Box 14)
  - Massachusetts--Boston--Buildings, 1859 - 1900 (Box 14)
  - Massachusetts--Boston--Charlestown, 1869 - 1899 (Box 14)
  - Massachusetts--Boston--Cemeteries, Parks, Monuments, After 1859 (Box 14)
  - Massachusetts--Boston--Cemeteries, Parks, Monuments, After 1859 (Box 15)
  - Massachusetts--Boston--Fire, 1872 (Box 15)
  - Massachusetts--Cambridge, 1859 - 1903 (Box 15)
  - Massachusetts--Cape Ann, 1860 - [188-] (Box 15)
  - Massachusetts--East Lee, 1886 (Box 15)
  - Massachusetts--Fall River, [1870] - [1879] (Box 15)
  - Massachusetts--Great Barrington, [187-] - [188-] (Box 15)
  - Massachusetts--Hoosac tunnel, 1865 - [188-] (Box 15)
  - Massachusetts--Martha's Vineyard, 1870 - [188-] (Box 15)
  - Massachusetts--Martha's Vineyard, 1870 - [188-] (Box 16)
  - Massachusetts--Mount Holyoke, [186-] - [187-] (Box 16)
  - Massachusetts--Nahant, 1860 - [188-] (Box 16)
  - Massachusetts--Nantucket, [186-] - [188-] (Box 16)
  - Massachusetts--New Bedford, [187-] -[188-] (Box 16)
  - Massachusetts--Newburyport, [186-] - [187-] (Box 16)
  - Massachusetts--Nonquitt, [1870] - [1879] (Box 16)
  - Massachusetts--North Adams, [186-] - [187-] (Box 16)
  - Massachusetts--Plymouth, 1859 - [188-] (Box 16)
  - Massachusetts--Provincetown, [187-] -[188-] (Box 16)
  - Massachusetts--Salem, [186-] - [188-] (Box 16)
  - Massachusetts--Springfield, [187-] -[188-] (Box 16)
  - Massachusetts--Worcester, 1870 - [188-] (Box 16)
  - Michigan, 1865 - 1900 (Box 16)
  - Michigan--Detroit, 1861 - [188-] (Box 16)
  - Michigan--Mackinac Island, 1860 - [188-] (Box 16)
  - Michigan--Mining, [ca. 1865-ca. 1900] (Box 17)
  - Michigan--Pineries, [ca. 1870-ca. 1880] (Box 17)
  - Minnesota, [ca. 1865-1905] (Box 17)
  - Minnesota--Duluth, [ca. 1869-ca. 1910] (Box 17)
  - Minnesota--Falls of St. Anthony, [1865-ca. 1880] (Box 17)
  - Minnesota--Fort Snelling, [1862-ca. 1880] (Box 17)
  - Minnesota--Granite Falls, [ca. 1880] (Box 17)
  - Minnesota--Lake Superior, [1868-ca. 1880] (Box 17)
  - Minnesota--Minneapolis, [ca. 1865-ca. 1910] (Box 17)
  - Minnesota--Minnehaha Falls, [ca. 1865-1906] (Box 17)
  - Minnesota--Pineries, [ca. 1870] (Box 17)
  - Minnesota--St. Paul, 1865-1903 (Box 17)
  - Mississippi, undated (Box 17)
  - Mississippi River, [187--188-] (Box 17)
  - Missouri, [ca. 187-] (Box 18)
  - Missouri--Saint Louis, 1864-1903 (Box 18)
  - Missouri--Saint Louis--Louisiana Purchase Exhibition, 1904 (Box 18)
  - Montana, [187--1904] (Box 18)
  - Nebraska, [1859-ca. 1910] (Box 18)
  - Nebraska--Excursion to the 100th Meridian, 1866 (Box 18)
  - Nebraska--Kearney, [ca. 1875?] (Box 18)
  - Nebraska--Omaha, [ca. 1860-188-] (Box 18)
  - Nevada, [1865-187-] (Box 18)
  - Nevada--Virginia City, [1865-188-] (Box 18)
  - New Hampshire, [1864-ca. 1900] (Box 18)
  - New Hampshire--Center Harbor; Lake Winnipesaukee, [186--1888] (Box 18)
  - New Hampshire--Concord, [ca. 1864-188-] (Box 18)
  - New Hampshire--Crawford or White Mountain Notch, [ca. 1865-1891] (Box 19)
  - New Hampshire--Franconia Notch, [ca. 1860-189-] (Box 19)
  - New Hampshire--Glen Ellis, Glen House & vicinity, [ca. 1860-189-] (Box 19)
  - New Hampshire--Isles of Shoals, [ca. 1875] (Box 19)
  - New Hampshire--Keene, [1868-188-] (Box 19)
  - New Hampshire--Mount Washington, [1860-189-] (Box 19)
  - New Hampshire--Mount Washington--Railroad, [186--1890] (Box 20)
  - New Hampshire--North Conway, [ca. 1860-1896] (Box 20)
  - New Hampshire--White Mountains, [ca. 1860-189-] (Box 20)
  - New Jersey, [ca. 1858-ca. 1910] (Box 20)
  - New Jersey--Asbury Park, 1871-1901 (Box 20)
  - New Jersey--Atlantic City, [188--1905] (Box 21)
  - New Jersey--Cape May, [ca. 1865-188-] (Box 21)
  - New Jersey--Hoboken, [ca. 1870] (Box 21)
  - New Jersey--Jersey City, [ca. 1868-189-] (Box 21)
  - New Jersey--Long Branch, [ca. 1869189-] (Box 21)
  - New Jersey--Morristown, [187-] (Box 21)
  - New Jersey--Ocean Grove, [ca. 1870-188-] (Box 21)
  - New Jersey--Paterson, [ca. 1859-ca. 1910] (Box 21)
  - New Jersey--Point Breeze, [ca. 187-] (Box 21)
  - New Jersey--Shrewsbury, [ca. 1875] (Box 21)
  - New Mexico, [1872-189-] (Box 21)
  - New Mexico--Albuquerque, [188-] (Box 21)
  - New Mexico--Indians, [ca. 1878-ca.1885] (Box 21)
  - New Mexico--Mining, [188-] (Box 22)
  - New Mexico--Santa Fe, [1867-188-] (Box 22)
  - New York, [187--194-] (Box 22)
  - New York--Adirondacks, [ca. 1865-188-] (Box 22)
  - New York--Albany, [186--1909] (Box 22)
  - New York--Andes, [ca. 1880] (Box 22)
  - New York--Auburn, [187-] (Box 22)
  - New York--Ausable Chasm, [187--188-] (Box 22)
  - New York--Beacon, 1959 (Box 22)
  - New York--Bear Mountain, 1959 (Box 22)
  - New York--Blooming Grove, [ca. 1880] (Box 22)
  - New York--Bronxville, [186-] (Box 22)
  - New York--Buffalo, [ca. 1868-1897] (Box 22)
  - New York--Buffalo--Pan-American Exposition, 1901-1902 (Box 22)
  - New York--Canals, [ca. 188-] (Box 22)
  - New York--Canandaigua, [ca. 1862-ca. 1874] (Box 23)
  - New York--Cardiff, 1869 (Box 23)
  - New York--Catskill Mountains and vicinity, [ca. 1859-189-] (Box 23)
  - New York--Champlain Canal, [194-] (Box 23)
  - New York--Chautauqua Lake, [ca. 1880] (Box 23)
  - New York--Cohoes, [187-] (Box 23)
  - New York--Cold Spring, [ca. 1865-188-] (Box 23)
  - New York--Conesus Lake, [187-] (Box 23)
  - New York--Cooperstown, [187--188-] (Box 23)
  - New York--Corning, [ca. 1880] (Box 23)
  - New York--Cornwall, [ca. 1862-188-] (Box 23)
  - New York--Croton, 187-, 1959 (Box 24)
  - New York--Crown Point, [187--188-] (Box 24)
  - New York--Dansville, [187-] (Box 24)
  - New York--East Greenwich, [ca. 1880] (Box 24)
  - New York--Elmira, [ca. 1868-ca. 1880] (Box 24)
  - New York--Fishkill, [ca. 1865-ca. 1875] (Box 24)
  - New York--Garrison, [ca. 1870] (Box 24)
  - New York--Geneva, [ca. 1870] (Box 24)
  - New York--Glenham, [ca. 1870] (Box 24)
  - New York--Glenora on Lake Seneca, [ca. 1875] (Box 24)
  - New York--Glens Falls, [187--188-] (Box 24)
  - New York--Green Lake, [188-?] (Box 24)
  - New York--Greenbush Heights, [188-] (Box 24)
  - New York--Greenwich, [187-] (Box 24)
  - New York--Havana Glen, [187--191-] (Box 24)
  - New York--Herkimer, [187--190-] (Box 24)
  - New York--High Falls, [187-] (Box 24)
  - New York--Honeoye Falls, [186-] (Box 24)
  - New York--Hornellsville, [187-] (Box 24)
  - New York--Hudson River, [ca. 1859-194-] (Box 24)
  - New York--Hudson River--Palisades, [ca. 1860-188-] (Box 24)
  - New York--Ilion, [ca. 1880] (Box 25)
  - New York--Idlewild, [ca. 1860-188-] (Box 25)
  - New York--Ithaca, [187--188-] (Box 25)
  - New York--Kingston, [ca. 1881] (Box 25)
  - New York--Lake Champlain, [186--188-] (Box 25)
  - New York--Lake George, [ca. 1865-188-] (Box 25)